and it reflects and echoes back off objects in their environment, and the bats then hear these echoes and they turn this information into an acoustic image. And this enables them to orient in complete darkness. Indeed, they do look very strange. We're humans. We're a visual species. When scientists first realized that bats were actually using sound to be able to fly and orient and move at night, we didn't believe it. For a hundred years, despite evidence to show that this is what they were doing, we didn't believe it. Now, if you look at this bat, it looks a little bit alien. Indeed, the very famous philosopher Thomas Nagel once said, "To truly experience an alien life form on this planet, you should lock yourself inside a room with a flying, echolocating bat in complete darkness." And if you look at the actual physical characteristics on the face of this beautiful horseshoe bat, you see a lot of these characteristics are dedicated to be able to make sound and perceive it. Very big ears, strange nose leaves, but teeny-tiny eyes. So again, if you just look at this bat, you realize sound is very important for its survival. Most bats look like the previous one. However, there are a group that do not use echolocation. They do not perceive their environment using sound, and these are the flying foxes. If anybody has ever been lucky enough to be in Australia, you've seen them coming out of the Botanic Gardens in Sydney, and if you just look at their face, you can see they have much, much larger eyes and much smaller ears. So among and within bats is a huge variation in their ability to use sensory perception. Now this is going to be important for what I'm going to tell you later during the talk. Now, if the idea of bats in your belfry terrifies you, and I know some people probably are feeling a little sick looking at very large images of bats, that's probably not that surprising, because here in Western culture, bats have been demonized. Really, of course the famous book "Dracula," written by a fellow Northside Dubliner Bram Stoker, probably is mainly responsible for this. However, I also think it's got to do with the fact that bats come out at night, and we don't really understand them. We're a little frightened by things that can perceive the world slightly differently than us. Bats are usually synonymous with some type of evil events. They are the perpetrators in horror movies, such as this famous "Nightwing." Also, if you think about it, demons always have bat wings, whereas birds, they typically -- or angels have bird wings. Now, this is Western society, and what I hope to do tonight is to convince you of the Chinese traditional culture, that they perceive bats as creatures that bring good luck, and indeed, if you walk into a Chinese home, you may see an image such as this. This is considered the Five Blessings. The Chinese word for "bat" sounds like the Chinese word for "happiness," and they believe that bats bring wealth, health, longevity, virtue and serenity. And indeed, in this image, you have a picture of longevity surrounded by five bats. And what I want to do tonight is to talk to you and to show you that at least three of these blessings are definitely represented by a bat, and that if we study bats we will get nearer to getting each of these blessings. So, wealth -- how can a bat possibly bring us wealth? Now as I said before, bats are essential for our ecosystems to function correctly. And why is this? Bats in the tropics are major pollinators of many plants. They also feed on fruit, and they disperse the seeds of these fruits. Bats are responsible for pollinating the tequila plant, and this is a multi-million dollar industry in Mexico. So indeed, we need them for our ecosystems to function properly. Without them, it's going to be a problem. But most bats are voracious insect predators. It's been estimated in the U.S., in a tiny colony of big brown bats, that they will feed on over a million insects a year, and in the United States of America, right now bats are being threatened by a disease known as white-nose syndrome. It's working its way slowly across the U.S. and wiping out populations of bats, and scientists have estimated that 1,300 metric tons of insects a year are now remaining in the ecosystems due to the loss of bats. Bats are also threatened in the U.S. by their attraction to wind farms. Again, right now bats are looking at a little bit of a problem. They're going to -- They are very threatened in the United States of America alone. Now how can this help us? Well, it has been calculated that if we were to remove bats from the equation, we're going to have to then use insecticides to remove all those pest insects that feed on our agricultural crops. And for one year in the U.S. alone, it's estimated
se refleja en los objetos y produce ecos en el entorno, los murciélagos escuchan esos ecos y esa información la transforman en una imagen acústica. Esto les permite orientarse en completa oscuridad. De hecho, los murciélagos se ven raros. Nosotros somos humanos. Somos una especie visual. Cuando los científicos descubrieron que los murciélagos en realidad usaban el sonido para volar, orientarse y moverse en la noche, no lo creímos. Durante cien años y a pesar de lo que mostraba la evidencia sobre lo que hacían, no lo creímos. Si uno mira a un murciélago parece un poco extraterrestre. De hecho, Thomas Nagel, un filósofo famoso dijo una vez que "para experimentar una forma de vida extraterrestre en este planeta, basta con encerrarse en un cuarto oscuro con un murciélago que esté volando y usando la ecolocalización". Y si vemos las verdaderas características físicas en la cara de este hermoso "murciélago herradura", apreciamos que muchas de ellas están destinadas a emitir un sonido y percibirlo. Orejas muy grandes, nariz extraña lanceolada, pero ojos muy pequeños. Así que si miramos de nuevo a un murciélago, nos damos cuenta de que el sonido es muy importante para su supervivencia. La mayoría de los murciélagos se parecen al anterior. Aunque hay un grupo que no usa la ecolocalización. No perciben su entorno utilizando el sonido. Este grupo es el de los murciélagos zorros. Si alguien ha tenido la buena suerte de estar en Australia, los habrá visto en el Jardín Botánico de Sidney, y si les miras la cara, observarás que tienen ojos mucho más grandes y orejas mucho más pequeñas. Así que hay una gran variación entre los murciélagos en cuanto a su habilidad para usar la percepción sensorial. Ahora esto va a ser importante para lo que les voy a decir más adelante en esta charla. Ahora, si la idea de murciélagos en tu campanario te aterroriza, y sé que alguna gente probablemente se siente un poco mal viendo imágenes muy grandes de murciélagos, probablemente no sea tan sorprendente, porque aquí en la cultura Occidental, los murciélagos han sido demonizados. Realmente, desde luego el famoso libro de "Drácula", escrito por un compatriota del norte de Dublín, Bram Stoker, probablemente sea el principal responsable de esto. De todas formas, también creo que tiene que ver con el hecho de que los murciélagos salen por la noche, y nosotros realmente no los entendemos. Estamos un poco asustados por las cosas que perciben al mundo ligeramente diferente a nosotros. A los murciélagos generalmente se los asocia con eventos malvados son agresores en películas de terror, como la famosa "Nightwing" también, si se ponen a pensar, los demonios siempre tienen alas de murciélago, mientras que los ángeles normalmente tienen alas de pájaro ahora, esta es la sociedad occidental, y lo que espero hacer hoy es convencerlos de la cultura tradicional china, que percibe a los murciélagos como criaturas que traen buena suerte y, de hecho, si entras a una casa china, tal vez veas una imagen como esta. Esto es considerado las 5 bendiciones. La palabra china para "murciélago" suena como la palabra china para "felicidad", y ellos creen que los murciélagos traen riqueza, salud, longevidad, virtud y serenidad. y de hecho, en esta imagen, tienen una foto de longevidad rodeada por 5 murciélagos. Lo que quiero hacer esta noche es hablarles y enseñarles que al menos 3 de estas bendiciones son definitivamente representadas por un murciélago, y que si los estudiamos estaremos cerca de alcanzar cada una de estas bendiciones Bueno, riqueza... ¿cómo un murciélago nos puede dar riqueza? Como dije antes, los murciélagos son esenciales para que nuestros ecosistemas funcionen correctamente. ¿Por qué? Los murciélagos tropicales son los mayores polinizadores de muchas plantas. También comen fruta y dispersan las semillas de estas frutas. Los murciélagos son responsables de polinizar la planta de tequila, y esta es una industria multimillonaria en México. Entonces, los necesitamos para que nuestros ecosistemas funcionen bien. Sin ellos, sería un problema. Pero la mayoría de los murciélagos son depredadores de insectos. Se estima que una colonia pequeña de grandes murciélagos pardos en EUA, comerá más de un millón de insectos al año, y actualmente en Estados Unidos los murciélagos están amenazados por una enfermedad llamada el síndrome de la nariz blanca. Está avanzando lentamente a través de EUA y eliminando poblaciones de murciélagos y científicos han estimado que 1300 toneladas métricas de insectos por año están quedando en el ecosistema a causa de la perdida de murciélagos. Los murciélagos también son amenazados en EUA por su atracción a los parques eólicos. Otra vez, los murciélagos se están viendo como un problema. Ellos van a... están muy amenazados en los Estados Unidos nada más. Ahora, ¿cómo nos puede ayudar esto? Bueno, ha sido calculado que si eliminamos a los murciélagos de la ecuación, vamos a tener que usar insecticidas para eliminar todas esas pestes de insectos que se comen nuestros productos agrícolas. Y por un año (solo en EUA) se estima
that it's going to cost 22 billion U.S. dollars, if we remove bats. So indeed, bats then do bring us wealth. They maintain the health of our ecosystems, and also they save us money. So again, that's the first blessing. Bats are important for our ecosystems. And what about the second? What about health? Inside every cell in your body lies your genome. Your genome is made up of your DNA, your DNA codes for proteins that enable you to function and interact and be as you are. Now since the new advancements in modern molecular technologies, it is now possible for us to sequence our own genome in a very rapid time and at a very, very reduced cost. Now when we've been doing this, we've realized that there's variations within our genome. So I want you to look at the person beside you. Just have a quick look. And what we need to realize is that every 300 base pairs in your DNA, you're a little bit different. And one of the grand challenges right now in modern molecular medicine is to work out whether this variation makes you more susceptible to diseases, or does this variation just make you different? Again, what does it mean here? What does this variation actually mean? So if we are to capitalize on all of this new molecular data and personalized genomic information that is coming online that we will be able to have in the next few years, we have to be able to differentiate between the two. So how do we do this? Well, I believe we just look at nature's experiments. So through natural selection, over time, mutations, variations that disrupt the function of a protein will not be tolerated over time. Evolution acts as a sieve. It sieves out the bad variation. And so therefore, if you look at the same region of a genome in many mammals that have been evolutionarily distant from each other and are also ecologically divergent, you will get a better understanding of what the evolutionary prior of that site is, i.e., if it is important for the mammal to function, for its survival, it will be the same in all of those different lineages, species, taxa. So therefore, if we were to do this, what we'd need to do is sequence that region in all these different mammals and ascertain if it's the same or if it's different. So if it is the same, this indicates that that site is important for a function, so a disease mutation should fall within that site. So in this case here, if all the mammals that we look at have a yellow-type genome at that site, it probably suggests that purple is bad. This could be even more powerful if you look at mammals that are doing things slightly differently. So say, for example, the region of the genome that I was looking at was a region that's important for vision. If we look at that region in mammals that don't see so well, such as bats, and we find that bats that don't see so well have the purple type, we know that this is probably what's causing this disease. So in my lab, we've been using bats to look at two different types of diseases of the senses. We're looking at blindness. Now why would you do this? Three hundred and fourteen million people are visually impaired, and 45 million of these are blind. So blindness is a big problem, and a lot of these blind disorders come from inherited diseases, so we want to try and better understand which mutations in the gene cause the disease. Also we look at deafness. One in every 1,000 newborn babies are deaf, and when we reach 80, over half of us will also have a hearing problem. Again, there's many underlying genetic causes for this. So what we've been doing in my lab is looking at these unique sensory specialists, the bats, and we have looked at genes that cause blindness when there's a defect in them, genes that cause deafness when there's a defect in them, and now we can predict which sites are most likely to cause disease. So bats are also important for our health, to enable us to better understand how our genome functions. So this is where we are right now, but what about the future? What about longevity? This is where we're going to go, and as I said before, I really believe that the secret of everlasting youth lies within the bat genome. So why should we be interested in aging at all? Well, really, this is a picture drawn from the 1500s of the Fountain of Youth. Aging is considered one of the most familiar, yet the least well-understood, aspects of all of biology, and really, since the dawn of civilization, mankind has sought to avoid it. But we are going to have to understand it a bit better. In Europe alone, by 2050, there is going to be a 70 percent increase of individuals over 65, and 170 percent increase in individuals over 80. As we age, we deteriorate, and this deterioration causes problems for our society, so we have to address it. So how could the secret of everlasting youth actually lie within the bat genome? Does anybody want to hazard a guess over how long this bat could live for? Who -- put up your hands -- who says two years? Nobody? One? How about 10 years? Some? How about 30? How about 40? Okay, it's a whole varied response. This bat is myotis brandtii. It's the longest-living bat. It lived for up to 42 years, and this bat's still alive in the wild today. But what would be so amazing about this? Well, typically, in mammals there is a relationship between body size, metabolic rate, and how long you can live for, and you can predict how long a mammal can live for given its body size. So typically, small mammals live fast, die young. Think of a mouse. But bats are very different. As you can see here on this graph, in blue, these are all other mammals, but bats can live up to nine times longer than expected despite having a really, really high metabolic rate, and the question is, how can they do that? There are 19 species of mammal that live longer than expected, given their body size, than man, and 18 of those are bats. So therefore, they must have something within their DNA that ables them to deal with the metabolic stresses, particularly of flight. They expend three times more energy than a mammal of the same size, but don't seem to suffer the consequences or the effects. So right now, in my lab, we're combining state-of-the-art bat field biology, going out and catching the long-lived bats, with the most up-to-date, modern molecular technology to understand better what it is that they do to stop aging as we do. And hopefully in the next five years, I'll be giving you a TEDTalk on that. Aging is a big problem for humanity, and I believe that by studying bats, we can uncover the molecular mechanisms that enable mammals to achieve extraordinary longevity. If we find out what they're doing, perhaps through gene therapy, we can enable us to do the same thing. Potentially, this means that we could halt aging or maybe even reverse it. Just imagine what that would be like. So really, I don't think we should be thinking of them as flying demons of the night, but more as our superheroes. And the reality is that bats can bring us so much benefit if we just look in the right place. They're good for our ecosystem, they allow us to understand how our genome functions, and they potentially hold the secret to everlasting youth. So tonight, when you walk out of here and you look up in the night skies, and you see this beautiful flying mammal, I want you to smile. Thank you. (Applause)
que va a costar USD 22 000 millones, si eliminamos a los murciélagos. Entonces, los murciélagos sí nos dan riqueza. Mantienen la salud de nuestro ecosistema, y nos ahorran dinero. Otra vez, esa es la primera bendición. Los murciélagos son importantes para nuestro ecosistema. ¿Qué pasa con la segunda? ¿Qué pasa con la salud? Adentro de cada célula de tu cuerpo está tu genoma. Tu genoma está compuesto por tu ADN, los códigos ADN para construir las proteínas que te permiten funcionar e interactuar y ser como eres. Ahora con los nuevos avances modernos de tecnología molecular, es posible determinar la secuencia de nuestro propio genoma en un tiempo breve y a un costo muy, muy reducido. Ahora que hemos estado haciendo esto, nos damos cuenta de que hay variaciones en nuestro genoma. Quiero que vean a la persona al lado de Uds.. Solo una mirada rápida. Y lo que tenemos que observar es que de cada 300 pares de bases en el ADN, tu eres apenas diferente. Y uno de los desafíos más grandes ahora en la medicina molecular moderna es descubrir si esta variación te hace más sensible a enfermedades o solo te hace diferente. Otra vez, ¿qué significa esto? ¿qué significa esta variación? Si queremos sacar provecho de los nuevos datos moleculares e información genética personalizada que está saliendo en línea, que vamos a poder tener en los próximos años, tenemos que poder diferenciar estas dos cosas. Entonces, ¿cómo hacemos esto? Bueno, yo creo que solo tenemos que observar los experimentos de la naturaleza. Entonces, a través de la selección natural, a través del tiempo, mutaciones, variaciones que interrumpen la función de una proteína no van a ser toleradas. La evolución actúa como un cedazo. Deja afuera las variaciones malas. Entonces, si observas la misma región de un genoma en muchos mamíferos que han estado evolutivamente distantes y que también son ecológicamente diferentes, vas a tener un mejor entendimiento de cuál es la evolución anterior de ese lugar, es decir, si es importante para que el mamífero funcione, para su supervivencia, será lo mismo en todos los diferentes linajes, especies, taxones. Entonces, si hiciéramos esto, lo que necesitamos hacer es decodificar esa región en todos los mamíferos diferentes y ver si es igual o diferente. Entonces si es igual eso indica que ese lugar es importante para una función entonces una mutación de una enfermedad debería caer en ese lugar. Entonces en este caso, si todos los mamíferos que analizamos tienen un genoma amarillo en ese lugar, probablemente sugiere que el morado es malo. Esto podría ser más poderoso todavía si observaras mamíferos que están haciendo las cosas un poco diferente. Digamos, por ejemplo, la región del gen que estuve viendo era una región que es importante para la visión. Si observamos esa región en mamíferos que no ven bien, como los murciélagos, y encontramos que esos murciélagos que no ven tan bien tienen el tipo morado, deduciremos que probablemente sea esto lo que está causando la enfermedad. Entonces en mi laboratorio, hemos usado murciélagos para analizar dos tipos diferentes de enfermedades de los sentidos. Estamos estudiando la ceguera. ¿Por qué harías esto? 314 millones de personas tienen problemas de la vista y 45 millones de estas son ciegas. Entonces la ceguera es un gran problema, y muchos de estos problemas de ceguera son hereditarios entonces queremos entender mejor qué mutaciones en el gen están causando la enfermedad. También observamos la sordera. Uno de cada 1000 recién nacidos son sordos, y cuando cumplamos 80, más de la mitad de nosotros va a tener problemas de audición. Otra vez, hay muchas causas genéticas para esto. Entonces lo que hemos estado haciendo en mi laboratorio es estudiar a estos especialistas sensoriales, los murciélagos, y hemos analizado los genes que causan ceguera cuando tienen un defecto, genes que causan sordera cuando tienen un defecto, y ahora podemos predecir qué lugares tienen la mayor probabilidad de causar enfermedades. Entonces los murciélagos son importantes para nuestra salud, para tener un mejor entendimiento de cómo funciona nuestro genoma. Entonces aquí es donde estamos ahora, pero ¿qué hay del futuro? ¿Y la longevidad? Aquí es a donde vamos a ir, y como dije antes, de verdad creo que el secreto de la eterna juventud está en el genoma del murciélago. Entonces, ¿por qué deberíamos estar interesados en el envejecimiento? Bueno, la verdad, esta es una imagen del siglo XVI de la fuente de la juventud. El envejecimiento es considerado uno de los aspectos más familiares pero menos entendidos de la biología, y la verdad, desde el principio de la civilización los humanos han tratado de evitarlo. Pero vamos a tener que entenderlo un poco mejor. Solo en Europa, en 2050, va a haber un 70% de incremento de individuos mayores de 65, y un 170% de incremento de individuos mayores de 80. Cuando envejecemos, nos deterioramos, y esta deterioración causa problemas en nuestra sociedad, entonces tenemos que enfrentarla. Entonces, ¿cómo podría el secreto de la eterna juventud estar en el genoma de un murciélago? ¿Alguien quiere adivinar cuánto tiempo podría vivir este murciélago? Quién --levanten sus manos-- ¿quién dice 2 años? ¿Nadie? ¿Uno? ¿Qué tal 10 años? ¿Algunos? ¿Qué tal 30? ¿Qué tal 40? Bueno, la respuesta es muy variada. Este murciélago es "myotis brandtii". Es el murciélago que más vive. Ha vivido hasta 42 años, y hoy sigue vivo en el medio silvestre. Pero ¿qué es tan impresionante de esto? Bueno, normalmente, en los mamíferos hay una relación entre el tamaño corporal, velocidad del metabolismo, y cuánto puedes vivir, y puedes predecir cuanto puede vivir un mamífero por su masa corporal. Normalmente, los mamíferos pequeños viven rápido, mueren jóvenes. Piensen en un ratón. Pero los murciélagos son muy diferentes. Como pueden ver en esta gráfica, en azul, estos son todos los otros mamíferos, pero los murciélagos pueden vivir hasta nueve veces más de lo esperado a pesar de tener una velocidad metabólica muy, muy alta, y la pregunta es: ¿cómo pueden hacer eso? Hay 19 especies de mamíferos que viven más de lo esperado, dada su masa corporal, que los humanos, y 18 de esas son murciélagos. Entonces, deben tener algo en su ADN que les permite lidiar con el estrés metabólico, particularmente de volar. Usan 3 veces más energía que un mamífero del mismo tamaño, pero no parecen sufrir las consecuencias o los efectos. Entonces ahora, en mi laboratorio, estamos combinando lo más avanzado en el campo de biología de murciélagos, saliendo y atrapando los murciélagos que han vivido mucho, con la más reciente, tecnología molecular moderna para entender mejor qué es lo que ellos hacen para impedir envejecer como nosotros. Y ojalá en los próximos 5 años, les pueda dar una charla TED sobre eso. El envejecimiento es un gran problema para la humanidad, y yo creo que estudiando a los murciélagos, podemos descubrir los mecanismos moleculares que les permitan a los mamíferos alcanzar una longevidad extraordinaria. Si descubrimos qué es lo que están haciendo, tal vez a través de terapias genéticas, podamos permitirnos hacer lo mismo. Potencialmente, esto significa que podríamos detener el envejecimiento y quizá hasta revertirlo. Solo imaginen cómo sería eso. Entonces realmente, yo no creo que deberíamos estar pensando en ellos como demonios voladores de la noche, sino más como nuestros súper héroes. Y la realidad es que los murciélagos nos pueden traer muchos beneficios si solo buscáramos en el lugar adecuado. Son buenos para nuestro ecosistema, nos permiten entender cómo funciona nuestro genoma, y potencialmente guardan el secreto de la eterna juventud. Entonces esta noche, cuando salgan de aquí y miren para arriba en los cielos de la noche, y vean a este hermoso mamífero volador, quiero que sonrían. Gracias. (Aplausos)